A Guide to the Dr. W. B. Conway and Julia Ellen Thomas Correspondence, 1869-1870
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Dr. W. B. Conway and Julia Ellen Thomas Correspondence, 1869-1870
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2014-015
0.5 cu. ft. 1 box
The Dr. W. B. Conway and Julia Ellen Thomas Correspondence contains letters exchanged between the couple from 1869 to 1870 before they were married.
Conway, Julia Ellen Thomas; Conway, William Buchanan, Dr., 1845-1919
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Dr. W. B. Conway and Julia Ellen Thomas Correspondence was donated to Special Collections in 2014.
Biographical Note: William B. Conway
Dr. William B. Conway was born in Ellerslie, Virginia, in 1845. Conway studied at Virginia Military Institute for a year, but left school to enlist as a private in Company C, 4th Virginia Cavalry. He served through the war, and afterwards studied medicine under the tutelage of Dr. Alfred Taliaferro at Culpeper Courthouse. He then studied at Washington University in Baltimore and graduated in 1869. Upon graduation, he left Baltimore to practice medicine at Mount Vernon Iron Works in Rockingham County, Virginia.
Biographical Note: Julia Ellen Thomas Conway
Julia Ellen Thomas was born in 1848 in Blacksburg Virginia the daughter of Col. William Thomas. Julia and William were married in 1870 and settled for a time in Blacksburg where William became a surgeon for the Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College (now Virginia Tech). They had five children: Daisy, Alfred, William, Archie, and Mary, all of which, except William, reached adulthood. Julia died in 1916. William died in College Park, Georgia, in 1920.
Scope and Content
This collection contains approximately sixty letters exchanged between Dr. William B. Conway and Julia Ellen Thomas (later Conway) during their courtship in 1869-1870. The letters discuss a number of topics including the couple's relationship, their families, mutual friends, and local and national events.
Arrangement
The letters in the collection are arranged chronologically.
Related Materials
W. B. Conway and Julia Thomas Conway Correspondence (Ms2019-018). Finding aid available online.
Julia Thomas Conway and Mary Black Thomas Luster Correspondence (Ms2019-019). Finding aid available online.
Catlett Conway Correspondence (Ms2012-039). Finding aid available online.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Montgomery County (Va.); Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College
Contents List
- Letters, 1869-1870
  - November 1869 (Box-folder 1-1)
  - December 1869 (Box-folder 1-2)
  - January 1970 (Box-folder 1-3)
  - April 1870 (Box-folder 1-4)
  - May 1870 (Box-folder 1-5)
  - June 1870 (Box-folder 1-6)
  - July 1870 (Box-folder 1-7)
  - August 1870 (Box-folder 1-8)
  - September 1870 (Box-folder 1-9)
  - October 1870 (Box-folder 1-10)
  - November 1870 (Box-folder 1-11)
  - December 1870 (Box-folder 1-12)
- Ephemera
  - Envelopes, 1869-1870 (Box-folder 1-13)